smartypig.com 2015-09-06

# SmartyPig®: Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

The _Privacy Policy_ can also be downloaded in [ Adobe® PDF](http://get.adobe.com/reader) format. Click the link below to save the Privacy Policy to your hard drive. 

Download Privacy Policy (PDF 115k)

Last Updated: February 18, 2015 

* * *

#### PRIVACY POLICY

In this disclosure, you'll find details about our privacy policies and procedures, and instructions for changing how information about you may be shared. Please read this carefully, print and/or download a copy for your files.

Your Savings Account with BBVA Compass is governed by the BBVA Compass Consumer Privacy Disclosure. Please see the BBVA Compass Consumer Privacy Disclosure for details on the BBVA Compass privacy policies.

This privacy policy applies to [www.smartypig.com ](http://www.smartypig.com/) owned and operated by SmartyPig, LLC ("SmartyPig"). This privacy policy describes how SmartPig, LLC collects and uses the personally identifiable information you provide on our web site: [www.smartypig.com ](http://www.smartypig.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personally identifiable information and how you can access and update this information.

SmartyPig, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements <http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/> including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiabe information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [www.smartypig.com ](http://www.smartypig.com/). 

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@smartypig.com](mailto:privacy@smartypig.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

#### SmartyPig Site Privacy Policy

We want you to make an educated choice, so please read this disclosure carefully to understand the options available.

  * We do not share customer information with third-parties for their own marketing purposes.
  * We may disclose the following information to our service providers: Information we receive from registration or other forms, such as your name, address, social security number and date of birth.
  * We safeguard our customer information carefully.
  * We are committed to protecting our customer information for every transaction, at every level of our organization. For this purpose, we have designed procedures, standards and technology, which are described in our policy.
  * We are committed to helping you protect your privacy every day.

#### Information Collection

We begin by safeguarding the security and integrity of customer information that we collect such as your name, address, financial information, social security number, email address, and date of birth. We are committed to protecting the security and integrity of customer information through procedures and technology designed for this purpose. For example:

  * We limit employee access to customer information to those who have a business reason to know this information. Employees are required to honor our code of conduct, which includes standards to protect customer confidentiality. They are subject to disciplinary action if they fail to do so.
  * We maintain policies and procedures covering the proper physical security of workplaces and records.
  * We ensure our physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards meet or exceed federal standards regarding the protection of customer information.
  * We require independent contractors and outside companies who work with us to adhere to strict privacy standards through their contracts with us. Privacy language is included in all contracts.
  * We use technological means (such as backup files, virus detection and eradication software, firewalls, and other computer software and hardware) to protect against unauthorized access or alterations to customer data.
  * We collect and maintain customer information as part of servicing your account and your customer relationship. In the course of serving you, we collect information about you from a variety of sources, such as: 
    * Information you provide to us on applications or forms.
    * Information we receive from an outside company, such as a credit bureau, regarding your credit history.
    * Information about your transactions or experiences with companies partnering with SmartyPig.

#### Use of Information That We Collect

Certain areas and features of SmartyPig.com are available to you without registration or the need to provide to us any information. However, there are times in which we do collect personally identifiable information and they are listed below:

  * In order to setup a SmartyPig account and benefit from the full functionality of the site, you must register and in doing so, provide us with the following personally identifiable information; name, residential address, social security number, phone number, gender, birth date and email address. This information is used by SmartyPig to verify your identity and communicate with you regarding the services requested and other account related activities. Once registered you may choose to open a savings goal and fund that goal with a personal funding source. In doing so, you will provide us with the following personally identifiable information: bank routing and account numbers.
  * In order to contribute funds to a SmartyPig user's public savings goal you must provide us with the following personally identifiable information: name, billing address, credit card information, phone number, and email address. This information is used by SmartyPig to process your order.
  * In order to purchase a SmartyPig gift card you must provide us with the following personally identifiable information; name, billing address, credit card information, phone number, and email address. This information is used by SmartyPig to process your order.

#### Profile Information

Once a user, you may provide additional information about your savings account(s), including what you are saving for, the savings category, if this is a public or private account, how much you wish to save, how much you have saved to date and when you wish to meet your goal.

#### Sharing Accounts

In order to invite others to contribute to your savings goals, you must designate a savings goal as being allowed to accept contributions. By doing so, you can then send e-mails to family members and friends inviting them to contribute to your savings goal, or family and friends can locate your savings goal by searching for your goal using your e-mail address. Your e-mail address will not be made public. The names and e-mail addresses of people whom you invite will be used only to send your invitation and reminders. Users can control the amount of information that is displayed on their savings goal-landing page, but it will not include more than the user's profile image, first name, last name, and description of what they are saving for, the total goal amount and their SmartyPig "friends." Users will have the option of displaying the current balance of the savings goal, the percent needed to reach the goal, or neither. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy.

#### Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by SmartyPig and our partners. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. 

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 or Flash to store [content information and preferences.] Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

#### Information About Your Friends

In order to invite others to your "friends" list, you will initiate a request from SmartyPig that they be added as a friend to your account. This information will be used by SmartyPig to send your one-time invitation. Your friend can then accept or deny the request. The names and e-mail addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation and will not be stored.

#### Testimonials

We receive permission to post testimonials prior to posting. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@smartypig.com](mailto:privacy@smartypig.com).

#### Blog

To post a comment, a user must include their name and email address. If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personally identifiable from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@smartypig.com](mailto:privacy@smartypig.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. To learn more please read our Terms and Conditions at at <http://www.smartypig.com/disclosures/terms-and-conditions>.

Our blog is also managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personally identifiable information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. 

#### SmartyPig Communications

SmartyPig will communicate with you through e-mail and notices posted on this Website. Please be aware that you will always receive certain e-mails from SmartyPig related to the proper function and activity of your account.

#### Customized Content

Information you provide at registration or in your Profile section may also be used to customize your experience on the Website.

#### Sharing Information With Third Parties

We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties.

We collect non-public personally identifiable information about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms.
  * Information about your transactions with us, our strategic partners or others.
  * Information we receive from consumer-reporting agencies.
  * Information we receive from identification verification agencies.

We may provide aggregated data about the usage of our services to third parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate. We may segment our users by savings category (i.e. electronics, home improvement). However, no non-public personally identifiable information about you will be included in this aggregate data.

#### Service Providers

We use other third-party service providers such as our banking, identity verification and retail gift card providers to provide services on our site. When you register on SmartyPig for an account, setup savings goals and redeem your funds, we will share personally identifiable information as necessary for the third-party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose including their own marketing purposes.

#### Security 

The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as your social security number and financial information) during registration, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [support@smartypig.com](mailto:support@smartypig.com).

#### Communications Between Users

SmartyPig allows registered users to send automated e-mail notifications to their family members and friends. Automated e-mails you send to a family member or a friend will come from [support@smartypig.com](mailto:support@smartypig.com).

The e-mail will include the following statement:  
"The following e-mail was sent to you on behalf of John Doe at <johndoe@example.com>"

#### Choice/Opt-out

SmartyPig users may choose to opt-in to receiving marketing information from selected partners, such as our banking service provider, BBVA Compass. This can be done during the registration process. Registered users may also opt-in to receiving this information at anytime under the Messages Settings section. Visit the BBVA Compass privacy policy at <http://www.bbvacompass.com/compass/policy/disclosure.cfm> for additional information. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [privacy@smartypig.com](mailto:privacy@smartypig.com).

You may not opt-out of receiving service related emails from SmartyPig that relate to the general usage of smartypig.com.

You will be notified when your personally identifiable information is collected by any third-party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

#### Legal Disclaimer

To the extent permitted by law, we may disclose personally identifiable information to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, or other legal process. We may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to perform charge verifications, report or collect debts owed, fight fraud, or protect the rights or property of SmartyPig, LLC, our customers, our website, or our users. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on our company or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

If SmartyPig is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. 

#### Accessing and Changing Your Account Information

You can review the personally identifiable information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information, or to the settings for your SmartyPig account, at any time by logging into your account on the SmartyPig Website and editing the information on your Profile page. You can also request to delete or that your information no longer be used by logging into your account or contacting us though any of our contact details listed below. When you close your SmartyPig account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable data. We may retain certain data contributed by you if it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non- personally-identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. All retained data will continue to be subject to the terms of the SmartyPig Privacy Policy to which you have previously agreed.

#### Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by SmartyPig. Please be aware that we, SmartyPig, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

#### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

#### Changes To This Privacy Policy

SmartyPig may update this privacy policy. In the event there are material changes in the way we collect and use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you here, via e-mail or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact SmartyPig Customer Support at 888-567-6278 or e-mail [privacy@smartypig.com](mailto:privacy@smartypig.com).

SmartyPig, LLC  
1271 8th Street, Suite 600  
West Des Moines, IA 50265-2651

Main Number: 515-256-2086  
Fax: 515-256-2091  
Toll Free: 866-576-2789
